Frank E. Fowle Collection MS089
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Frank E. Fowle Collection
1852 -- 1980
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Fowle, Frank E.
MS089
14.8 Linear Feet 26 boxes
Arrangement
Organized into four series: Playscripts; Playbills; Scrapbooks; Production notes.
Custodial History
Around 2003, this artificial collection was created out of material originally found in boxes containing Arthur W. Row papers, the Max Tennis collection, the Henry Y. Porter papers and the Scrapbook collection. Most of the material was well labeled with Fowle's name making it easy to identify.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains mostly programs and published and unpublished playscripts from amateur productions that Fowle was involved with in the greater Boston area. It also includes a series of scrapbooks from productions in the Boston area from 1883-1930.
Biographical / Historical
Frank E. Fowle was director of amateur theatricals in the greater Boston area especially between 1915-35.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Greater Boston arts; Fowle, Frank E.
- Playscripts, 1852 -- 1969; 1880 -- 1920; MS089.001; 5.05 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains published play-scripts from the late nineteenth to early twentieth century. An inventory book of these plays exits in the series. It also includes a number of adapted, typed play-scripts used by Fowle in productions he was involved with.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Typewritten playscripts, 1915 -- 1920; MS089.001.001
    Mostly re-typed and adapted plays which Fowle directed or produced.
    - A Romance in Bohemia, playscript, MS089.001.021.00001 (Box 21)
      Fowle, Frank E.
    - The Hottentot, playscript, MS089.001.021.00002 (Box 21)
    - The Dover Road, playscript, MS089.001.021.00003 (Box 21)
    - A Christmas Carol or the reclamation of Ebenezer Scrooge, playscript, MS089.001.021.00004 (Box 21)
      A dramatization by Frank E. Fowle of Charles Dickens' story.
    - The Tailor's Son, playscript, 1915; MS089.001.021.00005 (Box 21)
      A comedy in four acts by Franklin S. Owen, 1915.
    - If Love Were All, playscript, MS089.001.021.00006 (Box 21)
    - The Odd Man Out, a comedy in three acts, MS089.001.021.00007 (Box 21)
      By Harold Brighouse. Manuscript includes Fowle's blocking notes.
    - Nicholas Nickleby, a play in four acts, MS089.001.021.00008 (Box 21)
      Adapted from the Charles Dickens' novel by Frank E. Fowle. Three versions.
    - Nicholas Nickleby, Arthur Gride, Act II, Scene 1, MS089.001.021.00009 (Box 21)
    - Tom Pinch or The Chuzzlewits, playscript, MS089.001.021.00010 (Box 21)
      A dramatization by Frank E. Fowle of Charles Dickens' famous novel, Martin Chuzzlewit.
    - Unidentified, Fowle's copy, MS089.001.021.00011 (Box 21)
      Covered with Fowle's production notes. Includes acts I,II,III.
    - Unidentified, prompter's copy, MS089.001.021.00012 (Box 21)
      Includes promper's notes for acts I,II,III.
    - Taming of the Shrew, arranged by Frank E. Fowle, MS089.001.021.00013 (Box 21)
      Includes various drafts.
    - Unidentified playscripts, MS089.001.021.00014 (Box 21)
    - The Heir at Law, a comedy by George Colman the younger, MS089.001.021.00015 (Box 21)
      Adapted(?) by Fowle.
    - Grumpy, playscript, 1920; MS089.001.021.00016 (Box 21)
    - The Old Homestead, a play in four acts, MS089.001.021.00017 (Box 21)
      Includes Fowle's notes on the production.
    - Diplomacy, an adaptation of Victorien Sardou's play "Dora", MS089.001.021.00018 (Box 21)
    - The Guv'nor, playscript, MS089.001.021.00019 (Box 21)
    - The Merry Wives of Windsor, a comedy in five acts, MS089.001.021.00020 (Box 21)
      This acting version arranged by Frank E. Fowle. Includes Fowle's handwritten production notes.
    - Cock O' the Walk, Jones, H.A., MS089.001.021.00021 (Box 21)
      Includes blocking notes.
  - Published playscripts, 1852 -- 1969; MS089.001.002
    Alphabetical by title. See Fowle's catalogue by title in box 25.
    - Above the Clouds, 1876; MS089.001.022.00001 (Box 22)
    - All on Account of an Actor, 1915; MS089.001.022.00002; Wilson, Louise Latham (Box 22)
    - Always Intended, 1868; MS089.001.022.00003; Wigan, Horace (Box 22)
    - Agnes deVere, 1855; MS089.001.022.00004; Buckstone, J.B. (Box 22)
    - The Amateurs, 1914; MS089.001.022.00005; Robinson, Raymond M. (Box 22)
    - An Amateur Triumph, 1916; MS089.001.022.00006; Davis, Paul P. (Box 22)
    - American Beauties, 1901; MS089.001.022.00007; Seaman, Abel (Box 22)
    - Among the Breakers, 1870; MS089.001.022.00008; Baker, G.M. (Box 22)
    - Andy Blake, or The Irish Diamond, 1857; MS089.001.022.00009; Bourcicault, Dion (Box 22)
    - Antony and Cleopatra, MS089.001.022.00010; Selby, George (Box 22)
    - Anything for a Change, MS089.001.022.00011; Brooks, Shirley (Box 22)
    - The Arabian Nights, MS089.001.022.00012; Grundy, Sydney (Box 22)
    - Armand, 1852; MS089.001.022.00013; Mowatt, Anna Cora (Box 22)
    - As You Like It, 1907; MS089.001.022.00014; Shakespeare, William (Box 22)
      The William Warren Edition
    - Atrocious Criminal, MS089.001.022.00015; Simpson, J.P. (Box 22)
    - Aunt Charlotte's Maid, MS089.001.022.00016; Morton, J.M. (Box 22)
    - Aunt Susan Jones, 1916; MS089.001.022.00017; McBride, H. Elliott (Box 22)
    - Babes in the Wood, MS089.001.022.00018; Taylor, Tom (Box 22)
    - Bachelor's Bedroom, MS089.001.022.00019; Matthews, Charles (Box 22)
    - Barnaby Rudge, MS089.001.022.00020; Selby, Charles; Melville, Charles (Box 22)
    - Beecher's Recitations, 1874; MS089.001.022.00021; Smith, E.F. (Box 22)
    - A Belighted Being, MS089.001.022.00022; Taylor, Tom (Box 22)
    - The Bells, 1880 -- 1917; MS089.001.022.00023; Lewis, Leopold (Box 22)
      4 versions
    - Betsy Baker or Too Attentive by Half, MS089.001.022.00024; Morton, John Maddison (Box 22)
    - Bill, the Coachman, 1910; MS089.001.022.00025; Francis, John M. (Box 22)
    - The Birds' Christmas Carol, 1914; MS089.001.022.00026; Wiggin, K.D. (Box 22)
      In collaboration with Helen Ingersoll
    - Black-Eyed Susan, MS089.001.022.00027; Jerrold, Douglas (Box 22)
    - The Boor, MS089.001.022.00028; Tchekoff, Anton (Box 22)
    - Bombastes Furioso, MS089.001.022.00029; Rhodes, T.B. (Box 22)
    - A Breach of Promise, MS089.001.022.00030; Robertson, T.W. (Box 22)
    - Bristol Diamonds, MS089.001.022.00031; Oxenford, John (Box 22)
    - Jessie Brown, MS089.001.022.00032; Bourcicault, Dion (Box 22)
    - Brutus, or The Fall of Tarquin, MS089.001.022.00033; Payne, J.H. (Box 22)
    - The Burglar, 1903; MS089.001.022.00034; Cameron, Margaret (Box 22)
    - Buried Treasure, 1898; MS089.001.022.00035; Greene, R.F. (Box 22)
    - Caleb Stone's Death Watch, 1925; MS089.001.022.00036; Flavin, Marvin (Box 22)
    - A Cannibal Love Affair, 1923; MS089.001.022.00037; Lawrence, Reba. B. (Box 22)
    - Capuletta; or Romeo and Juliet Restored, 1868; MS089.001.022.00038 (Box 22)
    - A Case of Suspension, 1916; MS089.001.022.00039; Wilson, Louise Latham (Box 22)
    - Caste, 1890; MS089.001.022.00040; Robertson, T.W. (Box 22)
    - The Cat and the Cherub, 1912; MS089.001.022.00041; Fernald, C.B. (Box 22)
    - The Changling, 1908; MS089.001.022.00042; Jacobs, W. W.; Sargent, H. C. (Box 22)
    - The Cheat of Pity, 1914; MS089.001.022.00043; Middleton, George (Box 22)
    - The Child in the House, 1916; MS089.001.022.00044; Howard, Homer Hildreth (Box 22)
    - Choosing a Career, 1916; MS089.001.022.00045; Caillavet, G. A. de (Box 22)
    - Cinderella Burlesque, MS089.001.022.00046; Byron, H. J. (Box 22)
    - Cinderella, MS089.001.022.00047; Keating, Miss E.H. (Box 22)
    - Cinders, 1899; MS089.001.022.00048; Tinsley, Lily (Box 22)
    - College Chums, 1907; MS089.001.022.00049; Wills, Anthony E. (Box 22)
    - Comrades, 1877; MS089.001.022.00050; Baker, George M. (Box 22)
    - A Conjugal Lesson, MS089.001.022.00051; Danvers, H. (Box 22)
    - Cool as a Cucumber, MS089.001.022.00052; Jerrold, W.B. (Box 22)
    - The Country School, 1890; MS089.001.022.00053; Orne, M.R. (Box 22)
    - A Crazy Idea, 1897; MS089.001.022.00054; Hageman, Maurice (Box 22)
    - A Cup of Tea, MS089.001.022.00055 (Box 22)
    - Creaking Floors, 1930; MS089.001.022.00056; Whorf, R.B. (Box 22)
    - A Cricket on the Hearth, MS089.001.022.00057; Smith, Albert (Box 22)
    - A Couple of Million, 1917; MS089.001.022.00058; Hare, Walter Ben (Box 22)
    - Cut off with a Shilling, 1884; MS089.001.022.00059; Smith, S. Theyre (Box 22)
      Two copies.
    - Damon and Pythias, MS089.001.022.00060; Banim, John (Box 22)
    - Dan'l Druce, 1915; MS089.001.022.00061; Gilbert, W.S. (Box 22)
    - The Daughter of the Stars, MS089.001.022.00062; Brooks, Shirley (Box 22)
    - The Deacon, MS089.001.022.00063; Jones, Henry Arthur (Box 22)
    - A Dead Heat, 1896; MS089.001.022.00064 (Box 22)
    - Deborah, MS089.001.022.00065; Cheltnam, Charles Smith (Box 22)
    - Delicate Ground: or Paris in 1793, MS089.001.022.00066; Dance, Charles (Box 22)
    - Dentist's Clerk, 1877; MS089.001.022.00067; Von Culin, Everett (Box 22)
    - A Desperate Game, MS089.001.022.00068; Morton, J.M. (Box 22)
    - De Trouble Begins at Nine, MS089.001.022.00069 (Box 22)
    - A Difference in Clocks, 1900; MS089.001.022.00070; Livingston, Ethel (Box 22)
    - Dizzy's Dilemmas, 1904; MS089.001.022.00071; Brown, Charles Ingersoll (Box 22)
    - Doing for the Best, MS089.001.022.00072; Lacy, M. Rophino (Box 22)
    - Dombey and Son, MS089.001.022.00073; Brougham, John (Box 22)
    - Done on Both Sides, MS089.001.022.00074; Morton, J.M. (Box 22)
    - Dora, MS089.001.022.00075; Reade, Charles (Box 22)
    - Dream Faces, MS089.001.022.00076; Miller, Wynn (Box 22)
    - Dreams, or My Lady Clara, MS089.001.022.00077; Robertson, T.W. (Box 22)
    - Dunducketty's Picnic, MS089.001.022.00078; Williams, T.J. (Box 22)
    - East Lynne, MS089.001.022.00079 (Box 22)
    - Easy as Pie, 1953; MS089.001.022.00080; Asbrand, Karin (Box 22)
    - Elfie; or the Cherrytree Inn, MS089.001.022.00081; Boucicault, Dion (Box 22)
    - The Elopement of Ellen, 1905; MS089.001.022.00082; Warren, M.J. (Box 22)
    - The Elopement, 1937; MS089.001.022.00083; Wakefield, John Edwin (Box 22)
    - Embers, 1911; MS089.001.022.00084; Middleton, George (Box 22)
    - Eugene Aram, MS089.001.022.00085; Moncrieff, W.T. (Box 22)
    - A Family Affair, 1906; MS089.001.022.00086; Townsend, Charles (Box 22)
    - Fanchon, The Cricket, 1860; MS089.001.022.00087; Waldauer, Aug. (Box 22)
      From tale of Georges Sand
    - Fashion, or Life in New York, 1935; MS089.001.022.00088; Mowatt, Anna Cora (Box 22)
    - Fazio, MS089.001.022.00089; Milman, Rev. H.H. (Box 22)
    - Feed the Brute, 1909; MS089.001.022.00090; Paston, George (Box 22)
    - Fine Feathers, MS089.001.022.00091; Byron, H. J. (Box 22)
    - Flies in the Web, 1860; MS089.001.022.00092; Brougham, John (Box 22)
    - A Fool for Luck, 1889; MS089.001.022.00093; Browne, W.M. (Box 22)
    - For One Night Only, 1899; MS089.001.022.00094; Baker, Robert, M. (Box 22)
    - Forty Miles an Hour, 1925; MS089.001.022.00095; Gilpatric, Carolyn (Box 22)
    - Foster's Formula, 1969; MS089.001.022.00096; Asbrand, Karin (Box 22)
    - A Frat Invitation, 1911; MS089.001.022.00097; Murphy, Louise Boyce (Box 22)
    - The Freedom of the Press, 1894; MS089.001.022.00098; Baker, Emily (Box 22)
    - Freezing a Mother-in-Law, 1889; MS089.001.022.00099; Pemberton, T.E. (Box 22)
    - French Without a Master, 1915; MS089.001.022.00100; Bernard, Tristan (Box 22)
    - Fright, 1937; MS089.001.022.00101; Reach, James (Box 22)
    - A Game of Cards, 1875; MS089.001.022.00102; Hollenius, L.J. (Box 22)
    - A Gentleman from Idaho, 1889; MS089.001.022.00103 (Box 22)
    - Gentleman in Black, MS089.001.022.00104; Gilbert, W.S. (Box 22)
    - The Ghost Breaker, 1909; MS089.001.022.00105; Dickey, Paul; Goddard, Charles (Box 22)
    - Gilded Youth, MS089.001.022.00106; Young, C.L. (Box 22)
    - A Girl of the Century, 1912; MS089.001.022.00107; Dumont, Frank (Box 22)
    - The Girl Who Paid the Bills, 1909; MS089.001.022.00108; Rhoades, Nina (Box 22)
    - The Golden Butterfly, 1886; MS089.001.022.00109; Carlos, Frank (Box 22)
    - Good for Nothing, MS089.001.022.00110; Buckstone, J.B. (Box 22)
    - A Good Woman, 1914; MS089.001.022.00111; Middleton, George (Box 22)
    - Grandpa, 1912; MS089.001.022.00112; Smith Jr., S. Decatur (Box 22)
    - The Garrick Fever, MS089.001.022.00113; Planche, J.R. (Box 22)
    - The Greater Law, 1924; MS089.001.022.00114; White, Leonard C. (Box 22)
      Includes a handwritten letter by the author in the cover of the book, dated 1926.
    - The Greatest Plague in Life, 1865; MS089.001.022.00115; Spencer, W.V. (Box 22)
    - The Great Umbrella Case, 1883; MS089.001.022.00116; Baker, George M. (Box 22)
    - A Half Back's Interference, 1912; MS089.001.022.00117; Beebe, M.N. (Box 22)
    - Heart of Mid-Lothian, MS089.001.022.00118; Dibdin, Thomas (Box 22)
    - Hector, 1897; MS089.001.022.00119; Hageman, Maurice (Box 22)
    - Henry Dunbar, MS089.001.022.00120; Taylor, Tom (Box 22)
    - High C, 1916; MS089.001.022.00121; Rosenfeld, Sydney (Box 22)
    - His Father's Son, 1916; MS089.001.022.00122; Bridgeham, G.R. (Box 22)
    - Hold that Kiss, 1942; MS089.001.023.00001; Vreeland, Frank (Box 23)
    - Home Sweet Home, with varitions, MS089.001.023.00002; Swears, Herbert (Box 23)
    - How She Loves Him, MS089.001.023.00003; Boucicault, Dion (Box 23)
    - Hundred Thousand Pounds, MS089.001.023.00004; Byron, H. J. (Box 23)
    - A Husband to Order, MS089.001.023.00005; Morton, J.M. (Box 23)
    - The Hypocrite, MS089.001.023.00006; Smith, Sol (Box 23)
      Based on Moliere's Tartuffe
    - The Idiot Witness, MS089.001.023.00007; Haines, J.T. (Box 23)
    - If I Only Had a Million, 1915; MS089.001.023.00008; Powers, Jay Clay (Box 23)
    - Indian Summer, 1913; MS089.001.023.00009; Clark, B.H. (Box 23)
    - In Double Peril, 1903; MS089.001.023.00010; Patten, Gilbert (Box 23)
    - In for a Holiday, MS089.001.023.00011; Burnand, F.C. (Box 23)
    - The Importance of Being Earnest, 1913 -- 1917; MS089.001.023.00012; Wilde, Oscar (Box 23)
      Three copies.
    - In Nelson's Days, MS089.001.023.00013; Paull, H.M. (Box 23)
    - In the Trenches, 1898; MS089.001.023.00014; Seaman, Abel (Box 23)
    - Isoceles, 1917; MS089.001.023.00015; Hare, Walter Ben (Box 23)
    - It's Time for Remembering, 1956; MS089.001.023.00016; Asbrand, Karin (Box 23)
      A Memorial Day play for the Grades
    - Jane, 1900; MS089.001.023.00017; Nicholls, H.; Lestocq, W. (Box 23)
    - The Jilt, 1904; MS089.001.023.00018; Boucicault, Dion (Box 23)
    - Joe Simpson's Double, 1892; MS089.001.023.00019; Reid, Charles S. (Box 23)
    - Joint Owners in Spain, 1917; MS089.001.023.00020; Brown, Alice (Box 23)
    - Katharine and Petruchio, 1878; MS089.001.023.00021; Winter, William (Box 23)
      Edwin Booth's Prompt Book
    - Katherine and Petruchio, MS089.001.023.00022; Garrick, David (Box 23)
    - Katty O'Sheal, MS089.001.023.00023; Pilgrim, James (Box 23)
    - A Kettle of Fish, 1890; MS089.001.023.00024; Von Schoenthan, Franz (Box 23)
    - King Rene's Daughter, MS089.001.023.00025; Phipps, E. (Box 23)
    - The Ladies' Battle, MS089.001.023.00026 (Box 23)
    - Lady Deadlock's Secret, MS089.001.023.00027; Simpson, J. Palgrave (Box 23)
    - The Last Cashe, 1927; MS089.001.023.00028; Mackay, I.E. (Box 23)
    - The Last Loaf, 1876; MS089.001.023.00029; Baker, G.M. (Box 23)
    - Lavender and Old Lace, 1938; MS089.001.023.00030; Warner, Rose (Box 23)
    - The Law-Suit, 1915; MS089.001.023.00031; Benedix, Roderich (Box 23)
    - Led Astray, 1873; MS089.001.023.00032; Boucicault, Dion (Box 23)
    - A Legal Holiday, MS089.001.023.00033; Chase, F. E.; Balch, W. L. (Box 23)
    - Lend me Five Shillings, 1889; MS089.001.023.00034; Morton, John Maddison (Box 23)
    - Liberty Hall, 1900; MS089.001.023.00035; Carton, R.C. (Box 23)
    - Linda, The Pearl of Savoy, MS089.001.023.00036; Barnett, C. Z. (Box 23)
    - Little Emily, MS089.001.023.00037; Halliday, Andrew (Box 23)
      "David Copperfield"
    - The Little Rebel, 1883; MS089.001.023.00038; Coyne, J. Stirling (Box 23)
    - The Little Red Mare, 1908; MS089.001.023.00039; Young, O. E. (Box 23)
    - The Littlest Girl, MS089.001.023.00040; Hilliard, Robert (Box 23)
    - London Assurance, MS089.001.023.00041; Boucicault, Dion (Box 23)
      Blocking Book
    - Looking for Trouble, 1907; MS089.001.023.00042; Barnes, J.; Seaman, Abel (Box 23)
    - Lost in London, MS089.001.023.00043 (Box 23)
    - Madame is Abed, 1871; MS089.001.023.00044; Woodward, John A. (Box 23)
    - Mad as a Hatter, MS089.001.023.00045; Marshall, F.A. (Box 23)
    - Madonna, 1914; MS089.001.023.00046; Middleton, George (Box 23)
    - The Maid of Judah, MS089.001.023.00047; Lacy, M. Rophino (Box 23)
    - Marse Covington, 1923; MS089.001.023.00048; Ade, George (Box 23)
    - A Match in the Dark, MS089.001.023.00049; Dance, Charles (Box 23)
    - The Mayor and the Manicure, 1923; MS089.001.023.00050; Ade, George (Box 23)
    - Milky White, MS089.001.023.00051; Craven, H.T. (Box 23)
    - Miriam's Crime, MS089.001.023.00052; Craven, H.T. (Box 23)
    - The Mishaps of Minerva, 1910; MS089.001.023.00053; Porter, Bertha Currier (Box 23)
    - Miss Oliver's Dollars, 1908; MS089.001.023.00054; Callaway, Emile H. (Box 23)
    - The Money Spinner, 1900; MS089.001.023.00055; Pinero, Arthur W. (Box 23)
    - Monseigneur, MS089.001.023.00056; Archer, Thomas (Box 23)
    - More Blunders Than One, MS089.001.023.00057; Rodwell, T.G. (Box 23)
    - A Most Unwarrantable Intrusion, MS089.001.023.00058; Morton, J.M. (Box 23)
    - Mothers, 1914; MS089.001.023.00059; Middleton, George (Box 23)
    - M.P. (Member of Parliament), MS089.001.023.00060; Robertson, T.W. (Box 23)
    - Mr. Bob, 1894; MS089.001.023.00061; Baker, Rachel E. (Box 23)
    - Mr. X, 1875; MS089.001.023.00062; Rosenfeld, Sydney (Box 23)
    - Mrs. Briggs of the Poultry Yard, 1905; MS089.001.023.00063; Whiting, E.G. (Box 23)
    - Mrs. Tyler Second, 1908; MS089.001.023.00064; Osgood, Harry O. (Box 23)
    - Mrs. Walthrop's Bachelors, 1878; MS089.001.023.00065; Baker, G.M. (Box 23)
    - Mrs. Willis' Will, MS089.001.023.00066; Souvestre, Emile (Box 23)
    - My Awful Dad, MS089.001.023.00067; Matthews, Charles (Box 23)
    - My Brother's Keeper, 1872; MS089.001.023.00068; Baker, G.M. (Box 23)
    - My Turn Next, MS089.001.023.00069; Williams, T.J. (Box 23)
    - My Young Wife and My Old Umbrella, 1874; MS089.001.023.00070; Carlos, Frank (Box 23)
    - Navel Engagements, MS089.001.023.00071; Dance, Charles (Box 23)
    - Nettie, 1923; MS089.001.023.00072; Ade, George (Box 23)
    - The Nettle, MS089.001.023.00073; Warren, Ernest (Box 23)
    - Nevada, 1882; MS089.001.023.00074; Baker, George M. (Box 23)
    - Nicholas Flam, MS089.001.023.00075; Buckstone, J.B. (Box 23)
    - Nick of the Woods, 1898; MS089.001.023.00076; Medina, Miss L.H. (Box 23)
    - Noemie, MS089.001.023.00077; Robertson, T.W. (Box 23)
    - No Thoroughfare, MS089.001.023.00078; Collins, Wilkie; Dickens, Charles (Box 23)
    - Not If I Know It, MS089.001.023.00079; Morton, J.M. (Box 23)
    - Not So Bad After All, MS089.001.023.00080; Reeve, Wybert (Box 23)
    - Number One, Round the Corner, MS089.001.023.00081; Brough, William (Box 23)
    - Ruth Oakley, MS089.001.023.00082; Williams, T.; Harris, A. (Box 23)
    - To Oblige Benson, MS089.001.023.00083; Taylor, Tom (Box 23)
    - The O'Dowd, MS089.001.023.00084; Boucicault, Dion (Box 23)
    - O'Keefe's Circuit, 1920; MS089.001.023.00085; Gilpatric, Carolyn (Box 23)
    - Old Curiosity Shop, MS089.001.023.00086; Stirling, E. (Box 23)
    - An Old Garden, MS089.001.023.00087; Davies, Hill (Box 23)
    - The Old Guard, MS089.001.023.00088 (Box 23)
    - Old Head and Young Hearts, 1881; MS089.001.023.00089; Boucicault, Dion (Box 23)
    - Old Honesty, MS089.001.023.00090; Morton, J.M. (Box 23)
    - Old House on the Bridge, n.d, MS089.001.023.00091; Lacy, T.H. (Box 23)
    - The Old Lady, 1921; MS089.001.023.00092; Duffy, Bernard (Box 23)
    - The Old Peabody pew, 1917; MS089.001.023.00093; Wiggin, Kate D. (Box 23)
    - The Old School District, 1949; MS089.001.023.00094; Asbrand, Karin (Box 23)
    - Oliver Twist, MS089.001.023.00095; Almar, George (Box 23)
      As performed at the Winter Garden.
    - On Bail, 1914; MS089.001.023.00096; Middleton, George (Box 23)
    - On Change, MS089.001.023.00097; Von Moser, G. (Box 23)
      Arranged by Miss E. Lawrence.
    - One Hundred Years Ago, 1876; MS089.001.023.00098; Baker, George M. (Box 23)
    - One Summer's Day, 1900; MS089.001.023.00099; Esmond, H.V. (Box 23)
    - One Touch of Nature, 1906; MS089.001.023.00100; Webster, Benjamin (Box 23)
    - Our Mutual Friend, 1879; MS089.001.023.00101; Shattuck, Harriette, R. (Box 23)
      From Charles Dickens.
    - Ours, MS089.001.023.00102; Robertson, T.W. (Box 23)
    - Our Wife or, The Rose of Amiens, MS089.001.023.00103 (Box 23)
    - Pan in Ambush, 1921; MS089.001.023.00104; Patterson, Marjorie (Box 23)
    - Painter of Ghent, MS089.001.023.00105; Jerrold, Douglas (Box 23)
    - A Pair of Shoes, 1882; MS089.001.023.00106; Rosenfeld, Sydney (Box 23)
    - Palace of Truth, MS089.001.023.00107; Gilbert, W.S. (Box 23)
    - Pa's New Housekeeper, 1912; MS089.001.023.00108; Bird, C.S. (Box 23)
    - Past Redemption, 1903; MS089.001.023.00109; Baker, George M. (Box 23)
    - Payable on Demand, MS089.001.023.00110; Taylor, Tom (Box 23)
    - Pauvrette, MS089.001.023.00111; Boucicault, Dion (Box 23)
    - Peep O'Day or Savourneen Deelish, MS089.001.023.00112; Falconer, Edward (Box 23)
    - A Perplexing Situation, 1916; MS089.001.023.00113; Smith, S. Jennie (Box 23)
    - Petticoat Perfidy, MS089.001.023.00114; Young, Sir Charles L. (Box 23)
    - Playing With Fire, MS089.001.024.00001; Brougham, John (Box 24)
    - The Plays and Books of The Little Theatre, 1919; MS089.001.024.00002; Shay, Frank (Box 24)
    - The Poor Gentleman, MS089.001.024.00003; Coleman, George (Box 24)
    - Poor Pillicoddy, MS089.001.024.00004; Morton, J.M. (Box 24)
    - Post of Honor, 1872; MS089.001.024.00005; Sanders, Sydney (Box 24)
    - A Pretty Piece of Business, MS089.001.024.00006; Morton, Thomas (Box 24)
    - The Princess, MS089.001.024.00007; Gilbert, W.S. (Box 24)
    - The Private Tutor, 1907; MS089.001.024.00008; Whisler, E.J. (Box 24)
    - Punch and Judy, 1904; MS089.001.024.00009; Richmond, E.T. (Box 24)
    - The Queen's Heart, 1858; MS089.001.024.00010; Palmer, John W. (Box 24)
    - A Question of Honor, 1899; MS089.001.024.00011; Franklin, Sydney (Box 24)
    - Race for a Widow, MS089.001.024.00012; Williams, T.J. (Box 24)
    - Randall's Thumb, MS089.001.024.00013; Gilbert, W.S. (Box 24)
    - Rebecca's Triumph, 1879; MS089.001.024.00014; Baker, George M. (Box 24)
    - The Rebound, 1915; MS089.001.024.00015; Picard, L.B. (Box 24)
    - Red or White, 1895; MS089.001.024.00016; Browne, W.M. (Box 24)
    - A Reference Catalogue of Representative Plays by Well-Known Playwrights, 1925; MS089.001.024.00017 (Box 24)
    - A Regular Fix, 1890; MS089.001.024.00018; Morton, J.M. (Box 24)
    - A Rice Pudding, 1889; MS089.001.024.00019; Tiffany, Esther B. (Box 24)
    - The Robbery, 1921; MS089.001.024.00020; Kummer, Clare (Box 24)
    - The Romance of a Poor Young Man, 1859; MS089.001.024.00021; Edwards, Pierrepont; Wallack, Lester (Box 24)
    - Ruth's Romance, MS089.001.024.00022; Broughton, Fred W. (Box 24)
    - Ruy Blas, MS089.001.024.00023; Hugo, Victor (Box 24)
    - Satan in Paris, 1855; MS089.001.024.00024; Selby, Charles (Box 24)
    - Scrambled Eggs, 1922; MS089.001.024.00025; Mackall, Lawton; Bellamy, Francis R. (Box 24)